Guide to the Dwight Macdonald Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1864, 1888, 1912-1978; Series I; 23 linear feet (62 boxes)
  - General
    - The University of Massachusetts Press, 1971-1972 (Box 54, Folder 1305)
    - The University of Michigan Press, 1961-1963 (Box 54, Folder 1306)
    - The University of Minnesota Press, 1944, 1966 (Box 54, Folder 1307)
    - Untermeyer, Louis, 1948 (Box 54, Folder 1308)
    - Updike, John, 1961 (Box 54, Folder 1309)
    - Utley, Freda, 1950-1951, 1962, 1964, n.y. (Box 54, Folder 1310)
    - V (Box 54, Folder 1311)
    - van den Haag, Ernest, 1955, 1957-1958, 1963, 1972 (Box 54, Folder 1312)
      See also: box 143, folder 54
    - Vanden Heuvel, William, 1960 (Box 54, Folder 1313)
    - Vanderbilt, Arthur T., 1953 (Box 54, Folder 1314)
    - Vanguard Press, Inc.(*), 1947-1949 (Box 54, Folder 1315)
    - Veteran's Commission on Court Martial Cases, 1947-1948 (Box 54, Folder 1316)
    - The Victorian Society, 1964, 1966-1967, 1974 (Box 54, Folder 1317)
    - Vidal, Gore, 1962 (Box 54, Folder 1318)
    - Viereck, Peter, 1948-1952, 1954, 1962 (Box 54, Folder 1319)
    - View, 1942 (Box 54, Folder 1320)
    - The Viking Press, Inc., 1963, 1965-1966, 1968-1971, 1973, 1976 (Box 55, Folder 1321)
    - The Village Voice, 1959, 1962, 1967-1969 (Box 55, Folder 1322)
      See also: box 9, folder 202
    - Villard, Oswald Garrison
      See: box 34, folder 859
    - Vivante, Arturo, 1957-1960, 1962-1963, 1965 (Box 55, Folder 1323)
      See also: box 20, folder 509
    - Vivante, Elena, 1957, 1961 (Box 55, Folder 1324)
      See also: box 1, folder 1 box 4, folder 49
    - Vivas, Eliseo, 1946, 1960 (Box 55, Folder 1325)
    - Vogel, Amos, 1962, undated (Box 55, Folder 1326)
    - Vogel, Virgil J., 1944-1949 (Box 55, Folder 1327)
    - Voluntary Organizations and a World without War, 1964 (Box 55, Folder 1328)
    - von Hoershelman, Lola, [1931-1932?], 1939 (Box 55, Folder 1329)
    - von Hoershelman, Natasha(*), [1930-1934?], 1935, 1938,[1940s], undated (Box 55, Folder 1329)
    - von Keuhnelt-Leddihn, Erik, 1946 (Box 55, Folder 1330)
    - Voorhis, Jerry
    - Votaw, Albert N., 1945-1950 (Box 55, Folder 1331)
    - Wa (Box 55, Folder 1332)
    - Waldrop, Frank C., 1972 (Box 55, Folder 1333)
      See also: box 72, folder 70-72
    - Wall, Bernard
      See: box 15, folder 376 box 54, folder 1290
    - Wallace, Henry A., 1945-1947 (Box 55, Folder 1334)
    - Wallace, Robert, 1961 (Box 55, Folder 1335)
    - Walther, Frederick, 1945-1946 (Box 55, Folder 1336)
    - Walton, Richard J.
    - War Resisters League, 1946-1950, 1961, 1963-1965, 1967-1968 (Box 55, Folder 1337-1338)
    - War Resisters League(*), 1969, 1971-1973, 1975, 1977 (Box 55, Folder 1339)
      See also: box 28, folder 726 box 55, folder 340 box 55, folder 1344 box 127, folder 685-690
    - War Resisters League Fiftieth Anniversary Committee, 1973 (Box 55, Folder 1340)
      See also: box 34, folder 872 box 55, folder 1337-1338
    - Ward, John William, 1972 (Box 55, Folder 1341)
    - Warner, Perc, 1926-[1928?] (Box 55, Folder 1342)
    - Warner, Ruth L., 1924-[1926-1928?], undated (Box 55, Folder 1343)
    - Warren, Robert Penn
    - Washington Pacifist Fellowship, 1948 (Box 55, Folder 1344)
    - The Washington Post, 1965 (Box 55, Folder 1345)
    - Wasson, Robert Gordon, 1938, 1951 (Box 55, Folder 1346)
    - Watson, D. Stanley, 1966-1967 (Box 55, Folder 1347)
    - Watt, Ian, 1958 (Box 55, Folder 1348)
    - We - Wh (Box 56, Folder 1349)
    - Weaver, Robert C., 1961, 1966 (Box 56, Folder 1350)
    - Wechsler, Irving, 1939-1940-[1941?], [1943?], 1945-1946, undated (Box 56, Folder 1351)
    - Wechsler, James A., 1947, 1959-1961, 1963-1964, 1973 (Box 56, Folder 1352)
    - Weiczen-Giuliani, Leo, 1942-1943 (Box 56, Folder 1353)
    - Yglesias, José, 1948-1949 (Box 56, Folder 1354)
    - Weil, Richard, Jr., 1949, 1952 (Box 56, Folder 1355)
    - Weiland, Alfred, 1948-1949 (Box 56, Folder 1356)
    - Weinberg, Helen(*), 1963, 1972-1975, 1977 (Box 56, Folder 1357)
    - Weinberg, Herman G., 1961, 1967, 1970, 1972-1973, n.y. (Box 56, Folder 1358)
    - Weiss, Paul, 1955-1956, 1958, 1963 (Box 56, Folder 1359)
    - Wensberg, Erik, 1958, 1963, 1968, 1972-1973, 1975 (Box 56, Folder 1360)
    - West, James R., [1962?] (Box 56, Folder 1361)
    - West, Ray B., Jr., 1947-1948 (Box 56, Folder 1362)
    - The West African National Secretariat, 1946 (Box 56, Folder 1363)
    - Weston, Harold, 1945-1946 (Box 56, Folder 1364)
    - Weyl, W., 1948 (Box 56, Folder 1365)
    - Wheeler, Dinsmore(*), [1923-1928?], 1924-1925, 1926 January-Jun, 1926 September-[1926?], 1927-[1927-1928?], 1928 January-October-[1928-1929?] (Box 57, Folder 1366-1373)
      See also: box 65, folder 25
    - Wheeler, Dinsmore(*), 1929-1930 February (Box 57, Folder 1374-1376)
    - Wheeler, Dinsmore(*), 1930 March-July-[1930?], 1931-1935 May (Box 58, Folder 1377-1384)
    - Wheeler, Dinsmore, 1935 June-July (Box 59, Folder 1385)
    - Wheeler, Dinsmore, (*)1935 August-1939, [1939s?], 1940-1951, 1953, 1956-1958, 1962-1964, 1967, n.d (Box 59, Folder 1386-1393)
      See also: box 117, folder 590
    - Wheeler, Marion (Mrs. E.D.), [1924-1927?]-1928 (Box 60, Folder 1394)
    - Wheeler, Richard Page(*), [1924-1925?]-1926-[1927?]-1929, 1943-1945, 1947, 1953-1954, 1958, 1962, undated (Box 60, Folder 1395)
    - Wheeler, Robert
      See: box 119-120, folder 608-612 box 83, folder 240
    - Wheelwright, John Brooks, 1939-1940 (Box 60, Folder 1396)
    - Whipple, A.B.C., 1961-1962 (Box 60, Folder 1397)
      See also: box 60, folder 1398
    - White, E.B., 1961 (Box 60, Folder 1398)
      See also: box 60, folder 1397
    - White, Morton, 1956 (Box 60, Folder 1399)
    - Whitney, John Hay, 1963-1964 (Box 60, Folder 1400)
      See also: box 26, folder 672
    - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1968 (Box 60, Folder 1401)
    - Whittemore, Reed, 1945, 1959-1960, 1963-1964 (Box 60, Folder 1402)
      See also: box 17, folder 432 box 36, folder 923 box 96, folder 397
    - Who's Who in America, 1970-1971, 1973, 1975 (Box 60, Folder 1403)
    - Wi (Box 60, Folder 1404)
    - Wicker, Tom
    - Widick, B.J., 1938-1940, 1955 (Box 60, Folder 1405)
    - Willen, Pearl S.
      See: box 12, folder 299
    - Williams, Elgin, 1946 (Box 60, Folder 1406)
    - Williams, Myron R.(*), 1924, 1926, 1937, 1946-1947, 1951-1954, 1957-1958, 1961-1962 (Box 60, Folder 1407)
    - Williams, Oscar, 1964 (Box 60, Folder 1408)
    - Williams, William Carlos
    - Willingham, Calder, 1945-1946, 1948 (Box 60, Folder 1409)
    - Willoughby, Robin Kay, 1974 (Box 60, Folder 1410)
    - Wills, Garry
    - Wilson, Angus, [1957?], 1959 (Box 60, Folder 1411)
    - Wilson, Edmund(*), 1937-1938, 1948, 1953, 1959, 1965 (Box 60, Folder 1412)
      See also: box 9, folder 211 box 36, folder 903 box 48, folder 1171
    - Wilson, Sloan
    - Wise, James Waterman, 1945 (Box 60, Folder 1413)
    - Wiser, Arthur(*), 1945-1949, 1951-1952, 1954, 1956-1958 (Box 60, Folder 1414)
    - Wittfogel, Karl A., 1950, 1952 (Box 60, Folder 1415)
    - Wo - Wu (Box 60, Folder 1416)
    - Wohlstetter, Albert, 1944, 1948 (Box 60, Folder 1417)
    - Wolfe, Bertram D.(*), 1938-1939, 1941, 1943, 1947-1949 (Box 60, Folder 1418)
      See also: box 27, folder 715 box 36, folder 903
    - Wolfe, Thomas ("Tom")
      See: box 98, folder 403-407
    - Wolff, Eleanor, 1952 (Box 60, Folder 1419)
    - Wollheim, Richard, 1957 (Box 60, Folder 1420)
    - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom
      See: box 13, folder 332
    - Woodcock, George(*), 1944-1947 (Box 61, Folder 1421)
    - Woodcock, George(*), 1948-1960 (Box 61, Folder 1422)
    - Woodward, Comer Vann, 1969 (Box 61, Folder 1422)
      See also: box 38, folder 959
    - Workers Defense League, 1944-1946, 1948 1956 (Box 61, Folder 1423)
    - Workers Educational Society, 1945 (Box 61, Folder 1424)
    - Workers Party, 1948, 1956 (Box 61, Folder 1425)
    - Workers' Schools in Western Pennsylvania
      See: box 50, folder 1213
    - Workers Socialist Party, 1946 (Box 61, Folder 1426)
    - World, 1954 (Box 61, Folder 1427)
      See also box 10, folder 235 box 56, folder 1360
    - World Pacifist Meeting, 1948-1949 (Box 61, Folder 1428)
    - World Without War Council, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 1429)
    - Worsthorne, Peregrine, 1956, n.y. (Box 61, Folder 1430)
    - Worthy, William, Jr., 1945-1948, 1950-1951 (Box 61, Folder 1431)
    - WPAX, Inc.
      See: box 23, folder 576
    - Wyzanski, Charles E., Jr., 1955 (Box 61, Folder 1432)
    - X,- Y (Box 61, Folder 1433)
    - Yaddo, 1949, 1953-1954 (Box 61, Folder 1434)
    - Yale City Planning Forum, 1969 (Box 61, Folder 1435)
    - Yale Daily News, 1926, 1958 (Box 61, Folder 1436)
    - The Yale German Review, 1964 (Box 61, Folder 1437)
    - The Yale Law Journal, 1966 (Box 61, Folder 1437)
    - Yale Law School Film Society, 1971 (Box 61, Folder 1437)
    - The Yale Literary Magazine, 1960, 1967, 1970 (Box 61, Folder 1437)
    - The Yale Political, 1963 (Box 61, Folder 1438)
    - Yale Publishing Association, Inc., 1927 (Box 61, Folder 1438)
    - The Yale Review, 1958 (Box 61, Folder 1438)
    - Yale University, 1925, 1927 (Box 61, Folder 1439)
    - Yale University, Class of 1928, 1948, 1957, 1962, 1967, 1971-1973 (Box 61, Folder 1440)
    - Yale University Elizabethan Club, 1961, 1964, 1975-1976 (Box 61, Folder 1441)
    - Yale University John Dewey Society, 1954, 1960 (Box 61, Folder 1441)
    - Yale University Library, 1946-1947, 1963, 1973-1975 (Box 61, Folder 1442)
    - Yale University, Timothy Dwight College, 1961 (Box 61, Folder 1442)
    - Title: "Reales cédulas copiadas de un libro de la Real Audiencia que comprende desde el año de 1741 a 1750." Places: Mexico, Spain. Description: Copies of royal decrees, most of which are eighteenth century official documents on commerce, industry, political authorities and administration of the Mexican viceroyalty. 1563#1790, 1946, 1968, 1971-1972, 1975 (Box 61, Folder 1443)
    - Young People's Socialist League, 1939, 1944, 1948, 1967 (Box 61, Folder 1444)
      See also: box 55, folder 1327
    - Z (Box 61, Folder 1445)
    - Zabel, Morton Dauwen, 1940-1941 (Box 61, Folder 1446)
      See also: box 140, folder 11
    - Zaccaria, Cesare, 1944-1947 (Box 61, Folder 1447)
    - Zahn, Curtis, 1947, 1949 (Box 61, Folder 1448)
    - Zahn, Gordon C., 1962-1965 (Box 61, Folder 1449)
    - Zimmerman, Charles S.
    - Zoll, Stephen, 1969-1970 (Box 61, Folder 1450)
    - Zolotow, Maurice, 1943-1944, 1962 (Box 61, Folder 1451)
    - Unidentified (alphabetical by first name, A - H) (Box 62, Folder 1452)
    - Unidentified (alphabetical by first name, I-Z) (Box 62, Folder 1453)
    - Unidentified (miscellaneous) (Box 62, Folder 1454)
- Research and Writing, 1919-1978; Series II; 36 linear feet (77 boxes)
  Early Writings, Books and Pamphlets, and Shorter Writings are arranged chronologically. The Subject File is arranged alphabetically. The folder headings in Books and Pamphlets and Shorter Writings note the presence of research material, notes, drafts, proofs, and reader response but do not mention such routine items as tear sheets, editorial correspondence, and requests for reprint rights.
  The material in the Subject File was brought together by the archivist, but Macdonald's groupings at the folder level have usually been preserved, and his folder headings are presented as titles or subtitles in quotation marks. Closely related papers may appear under several headings e.g., "Draft resistance," "Pacifism," and "Vietnam."
  - Early Writings
    - Themes, 1919-1920 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Themes, drafts, clippings, [1920-1924?] (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Stories, themes, notes, examinations, [1920-1924?] (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Stories: "Barbara," "The Enemy," "The Wall," "Man Overboard", [1920-1928?] (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - "Book List of the Macdonald Library", 1921 January 1 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - The Exonian and The Phillips Exeter Monthly, 1921-1922 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - "The Diary of Dwight Macdonald Junior", [1922] (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Themes, 1922-1923, undated (Box 63, Folder 8)
      See also: box 1, folder 2-8
    - The Exonian, 1923 February-March (Box 63, Folder 9)
    - The Phillips Exeter Monthly, 1923 February-May (Box 63, Folder 10)
    - The Phillips Exeter Monthly, 1923 October-1924 October (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - "Masquerade," the Hedonists' magazine at Exeter, [1923-1924?] (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - Class poem, 1924 (Box 64, Folder 13)
    - Themes and miscellaneous writings, [1924-1928?] (Box 64, Folder 14)
    - The Yale Literary Magazine, 1924 (Box 64, Folder 15)
    - Reading list, [1924-1928?] (Box 64, Folder 16)
    - Letter to President Angell, 1925 December 1 (Box 64, Folder 17)
    - "My notebook", 1925 July 13-1926 August 24 (Box 64, Folder 18)
    - The Yale Literary Magazine, 1925-1926 (Box 64, Folder 19)
    - Scrapbook of clippings from The Exonian and the Yale Daily News, 1925-1927 (Box 64, Folder 20)
    - "The notebook of Dwight Macdonald", 1926 (Box 65, Folder 21)
    - The Yale Record, 1926 (Box 65, Folder 22)
    - "The Private Papers of Dwight Macdonald", 1926-1927 (Box 65, Folder 23)
    - Yale publications, 1927 (Box 65, Folder 24)
    - "The Homer Page Chronicle", 1928 June-August (Box 65, Folder 25)
    - Yale publications, 1928 (Box 65, Folder 26)
    - ["The Ohio Story"], [1928?] (Box 65, Folder 27)
    - "From Long Chronicle about Dot and Me, at Farm, Summer 1928", undated (Box 65, Folder 27)
    - Miscellaneous writings, [1920s?] (Box 65, Folder 28)
    - notebook, 1935-1936, undated (Box 65, Folder 29)
    - "List of Books to Read", 1936 (Box 65, Folder 30)
  - Books and Pamphlets
    - The Money Masters (unfinished book project): notes (Box 66, Folder 31)
    - Fascism and the American Scene: notes, draft, 1938 (Box 66, Folder 32)
    - Jobs Not Battleships!: reader response, 1940 January (Box 66, Folder 33)
    - The Responsibility of Peoples (reprint from politics, 1945 Mar) (Box 66, Folder 34)
    - Shall Europe, Starve? (pamphlet published by politics ), 1945 (Box 66, Folder 35)
    - Partir de Home…, Spartacus edition (France), 1948 July (Box 66, Folder 36)
    - The Root is Man, Cunningham Press edition: annotated copy, 1953 (Box 66, Folder 37)
    - The Root is Man, Modern Publishers edition (India), undated (Box 66, Folder 38)
    - Henry Wallace: The Man and the Myth
      - Research material, 1948 (Box 66, Folder 39-40)
      - Research material, notes, 1948 (Box 67, Folder 41-43)
      - notes, 1948 (Box 68, Folder 44)
      - Reader response, 1948 (Box 68, Folder 45)
        See also: box 6, folder 82 box 7, folder 136 box 14, folder 345 box 14, folder 346 box 15, folder 383 box 16, folder 392 box 16, folder 420 box 19, folder 475 box 21, folder 557 box 23, folder 598 box 26, folder 676 box 26, folder 679 box 26, folder 700 box 27, folder 706-707 box 34, folder 849 box 35, folder 878 box 36, folder 923 box 39, folder 982 box 41, folder 1012 box 42, folder 1027 box 42, folder 1035 box 44, folder 1081 box 44, folder 1089 box 46, folder 1126 box 49, folder 1183 box 49, folder 1189 box 51, folder 1251 box 55, folder 1334 box 56, folder 1352 box 60, folder 1418
    - The Ford Foundation: The Men and the Millions
      - Research material, 1956 (Box 68, Folder 46-48)
      - Research material, notes, 1956 (Box 68, Folder 49-51)
        See also: box 16, folder 1400 box 16, folder 415 box 27, folder 710 box 44, folder 1084
      - Research material, notes, 1956 (Box 68, Folder 52)
      - Research material, draft of unpublished article by Stephen White, 1956 (Box 68, Folder 53)
      - Research material, 1956 (Box 69, Folder 54-58)
      - Research material, 1956 (Box 70, Folder 59-62)
      - Research material, 1956 (Box 71, Folder 63)
      - Research material; notes on "Ford Foundation: Biographies," "East European Fund," "Behavioral Science Fund," "International Programs", 1956 (Box 71, Folder 64)
      - Research material; notes on "The Fund for The Republic, Inc.," "Cox and Reece Congressional Forays," "The Fund for the Advancement of Education", 1956 (Box 71, Folder 65)
      - Research material on "Ford Motors, stock sales, etc.", 1956 (Box 71, Folder 66)
      - notes, 1956 (Box 71, Folder 67)
      - Drafts, proofs, 1956 (Box 71, Folder 68)
      - Reader response, 1956 (Box 71, Folder 69)
        See also: box 5, folder 53 box 9, folder 210 box 10, folder 241 box 16, folder 1400 box 16, folder 415 box 26, folder 675 box 27, folder 710 box 44, folder 1084 box 45, folder 1107 box 56,folder 1359 box 61, folder 1432
    - Memoirs of a Revolutionist
      - notes, drafts, 1957 (Box 72, Folder 70)
      - Reader response, 1957 (Box 72, Folder 71-72)
        See also: box 43, folder 1065
    - Parodies: An Anthology from Chaucer to Beerbohm - and After
      - Research material, 1960 (Box 72, Folder 73)
      - Research material, notes, 1960 (Box 72, Folder 74-76)
      - Drafts, 1960 (Box 72, Folder 77)
      - Proof, 1960 (Box 72, Folder 78)
      - Proof, 1960 (Box 73, Folder 79-82)
      - Reader response, 1960 (Box 73, Folder 83-84)
        See also: box 9, folder 194 box 14, folder 354 box 15, folder 379 box 15, folder 387 box 16, folder 416 box 21, folder 547 box 33, folder 821 box 54, folder 1309
    - Against the American Grain
      - Draft, 1963 (Box 73, Folder 85)
      - Draft, 1963 (Box 74, Folder 86)
      - Reader response, 1963 (Box 74, Folder 87-89)
        See also: box 10, folder 230 box 10, folder 232 box 12, folder 309 box 19, folder 475 box 43, folder 1061 box 51, folder 1239
    - Poems of Edgar Allan Poe
      - Draft, 1965 (Box 74, Folder 90)
      - Proofs, 1965 (Box 74, Folder 91)
    - Politics Past: notes, draft, proof, 1967 (Box 74, Folder 92)
    - The Root Is Man, Grossman Publishers edition: research material, notes, drafts of "20 Years After: Foreword & Postscript", 1967 (Box 74, Folder 93)
      See also: box 12, folder 678
    - The "Politics" Reader: notes, draft, 1968 (Box 74, Folder 94)
    - My Past and Thoughts: The Memoirs of Alexander Herzen: research material, notes, drafts, 1968 (Box 75, Folder 95)
    - My Past and Thoughts: The Memoirs of Alexander Herzen: drafts, proof, 1968 (Box 75, Folder 96)
      See also: box 8, folder 147 box 25, folder 646 box 26, folder 675
    - Dwight Macdonald on Movies
      - Proof, 1969 (Box 75, Folder 97-99)
      - Reader response, 1969 (Box 75, Folder 100)
    - Controamerica, Rizzoli edition, 1969 (Box 75, Folder 101)
    - Translation of Neither Victims nor Executioners by Albert Camus, 1972 (Box 76, Folder 102)
    - Discriminations
      - Research material, 1974 (Box 76, Folder 103)
      - notes, draft, 1974 (Box 76, Folder 105-106)
      - notes, draft, proof, 1974 (Box 76, Folder 107)
      - Drafts, 1974 (Box 76, Folder 108)
      - "Redone Pages: Returned from Grossman," notes, drafts, edited proofs, 1974 (Box 76, Folder 109-110)
      - Reader response, 1974 (Box 76, Folder 111)
      - Drafts, edited proofs, 1974 (Box 77, Folder 112)
  - Shorter Writings
    - "Our Elizabethan Movies," The Miscellany draft of reprint (in Dwight Macdonald on Movies ), 1929 December (Box 78, Folder 113)
    - "The Modern Theatre: An Inquest," The Miscellany, 1930 March (Box 78, Folder 114)
    - "Robinson Jeffers: II," The Miscellany, 1930 September (Box 78, Folder 115)
    - "Eisenstein, Pudovkin and Others," The Miscellany, 1931 March (Box 78, Folder 116)
    - "Notes on Hollywood Directors," Symposium, 1933 Apr, July (Box 78, Folder 117)
    - "The Communist Party," Fortune: draft, 1934 September (Box 78, Folder 118)
    - "The Nervous Breakdown," Fortune: notes, 1935 April (Box 78, Folder 119)
    - "Notes on Spender and Auden" draft, [1935] (Box 78, Folder 120)
    - "Twelve of the Best American Schools," Fortune, 1936 January (Box 78, Folder 121)
    - "U.S. Steel: I-IV," Fortune: proofs, 1936 March-June (Box 78, Folder 122)
      See also: box 129-132, folder 708-729
    - "The Big Four of Steel," The Nation, 1936 August 29 (Box 78, Folder 123)
    - "An Open Letter to Dr. John Dewey": draft, [1936-1937] (Box 78, Folder 124)
    - "Laugh and Lie Down," Partisan Review: research material, notes, draft, correspondence, 1937 January (Box 78, Folder 125)
    - "Espionage, Inc.," The Nation, 1937 February 27 (Box 78, Folder 126)
    - "Time and Henry Luce,""Fortune Magazine," "Time, Fortune, Life," The Nation: reader response, 1937 May 1,8,22 (Box 78, Folder 127)
    - "Who Wouldn't Strike?" The Nation: research material, notes, unidentified draft of "Why We Are Striking", 1937 May 22 (Box 78, Folder 128)
    - "Form 'Lit' Editor Takes 'Old Lady' to Task in Review of Current Issue," The Yale Daily News, 1938 June 4 (Box 78, Folder 129)
    - "Pittsburgh: What a City Shouldn't Be," Forum: research material, notes, drafts, 1938 June (Box 78, Folder 130)
    - "They, the People," The New International, 1938 July (Box 78, Folder 131)
      See also: box 148-149, folder 24-28
    - "The Soviet Cinema 1930-1938," Partisan Review: reader response, 1938 July-Sep, 1939 Winter (Box 78, Folder 132)
    - "Reading from Left to Right," The New International, 1938 Dec, 1939 February-May (Box 78, Folder 133)
    - Column, The Northwest Organizer, 1939 March 9,16,23; April 21 (Box 78, Folder 134)
      See also: box 37, folder 948
    - Review of The School for Dictators by Ignazio Silone, The New International, 1939 April (Box 78, Folder 135)
    - "The Monopoly Committee," The American Scholar, 1939 Summer (Box 78, Folder 136)
    - "Twenty-five Million of Us," The New International: drafts, 1939 September (Box 78, Folder 137)
    - "Veinticinco millones de nosotros," Babel, 1939 November (Box 78, Folder 138)
    - Review of America Was Promises by Archibald MacLeish: draft, [1939?] (Box 78, Folder 139)
    - "DM's Ideas on Chinese Art": notes, [1930s] (Box 78, Folder 140)
    - "The Works of Charles Biederman": notes, drafts, [1930s?] (Box 78, Folder 141)
    - Statement on Joe Gould: draft, [1939-1940] (Box 78, Folder 142)
    - "WPA Cuts — or Jail," The Nation, 1940 February 3 (Box 78, Folder 143)
    - "London's Burning! London's Burning": research material, notes, draft, 1940 Fall (Box 78, Folder 144)
    - Partisan Review: reader response, 1940 (Box 78, Folder 145)
    - Letters to the editor, Common Sense, on Lion Feuchtwanger: research material, notes, draft, 1941 February 3 (Box 78, Folder 146)
    - "Intento de apreciacion," Babel, 1941 March-April (Box 79, Folder 147)
    - "The American War Economy," The New International, 1941 April (Box 79, Folder 148)
    - "Your Waiter Looks at You," Harper's Magazine: note by D. Macdonald about his informant, 1976, 1941 April (Box 79, Folder 149)
    - Review of Darkness at Noon by Arthur Koestler, Common Sense, 1941 July 1 (Box 79, Folder 150)
    - "Kulturbolschewismus is there," Partisan Review, 1941 November-December (Box 79, Folder 151)
    - "England at War, IV: How Totalitarian is Wartime England?": draft, [1941] (Box 79, Folder 152)
    - "Letter from Dwight Macdonald," Modern Socialism, 1941-1942 Winter (Box 79, Folder 153)
    - Review of Escape from Freedom by Erich Fromm: unidentified tear sheet, 1942 January (Box 79, Folder 154)
    - "Jesse Jones, Reluctant Dragon," The Nation, 1942 February 7,14 (Box 79, Folder 155)
    - "The (American) People's Century," Partisan Review, 1942 July-August (Box 79, Folder 156)
    - "The Eisenstein Tragedy," Partisan Review, 1942 November-December (Box 79, Folder 157)
      See also: box 80, folder 193
    - "Roosevelt's Conservative War," Partisan Review: drafts, 1942 November-December (Box 79, Folder 158)
    - "How U.S. Capitalism Goes to War," Left, 1942 December (Box 79, Folder 159)
    - Statement on democracy and totalitarianism: draft, [1942-1943] (Box 79, Folder 160)